This is ridiculous.
（ノノハ）バッカじゃないの！
うっせ～よ！
Shut up!
（アナ）カイト　動いちゃダメ～！
Kaito, don't move!
ああ　わりい　わりい。
Sorry, my bad...
全く　アナも　物好きよね。
カイトの絵を描きたいだなんて。
Seriously, you sure have a lot of free time...
Who would even want to paint Kaito?
アナが思うに　怖いもの見たさ～。
I think... I just saw something weird!
どれどれ？…　って！
なんじゃ　こりゃあ～～～！？
Let me see.
Huh?!
The hell is this?
カイト。
俺じゃねえし！
You.
That's not me!
人間かどうかも　分かんないし。
I can't even tell if it's human or not.
でも　カイトとなんだな～。
ね～　鳥友～。
But it's Kaito.
Right, birdies?
はははっ　…ったく
アナには　かなわねえよな。
Man...
Ana is out of our league.
自由すぎるぜ　アナはよ。
He's just so free.
（イブ）自由…　吐き気がするわ！
Free... Makes me feel sick.
lost te saguri de sagashiteta
Lost, trying to find it blindly with my hands.
tozasareta mirai no kotae nante doko ni mo nai
But the key to the locked future is nowhere to be found.
hashiru shoudou ima kaidoku funou
Undecipherable urges surging.
found kudaketa hazu no unmei wo
I found the fate I believed broken.
mijukuna yume no naka de kikoetekitan da
I heard it in my immature dream.
saigo made I'll be there for you
I'll be there for you till the very end.
tachitomaranai kono hari dake wa
I can't stop. I hear nothing else.
boku no asu wo kizamu oto tsukisasu
How this needle carves my future.
shinjitsu kara nigetara ima
I'm running away from the truth now.
genjitsu ni mo maketara ima
I'm losing to reality now.
nani ga nokoru no (nokoru no)
What will be left?
kazoekirenai kono kizu dake ga
The countless scars on my body
boku no kinou wo zanzou toshite kataru
are the only thing telling the story of my past.
unmei ga hodokete mo ima
Even if fate falls apart now,
sonzai wo kowashite mo ima
even if existence shatters now,
boku no michi wo yuku yo
I'm walking down my own path.
It's now or never.
This is what they say: "Live your life today."
There will always be, there will always be a way.
Pieces of Hatred
（ヘルベルト）大門カイトたちとの決闘に
負けたら　以後　接触を断つ。
If you lose against Daimon Kaito, you are never to attempt contact again.
そう　約束したそうだね。
That was the promise.
くだらん。　約束など
破るためにあるものだよ。
Laughable. Promises are made to be broken.
全く　君たちには　うんざりだ。
I'm getting tired of you all.
なぜ　クロンダイク様は　未来ある私を
君たちの指揮官になど　したのか？
Why did Lord Klondike recognize my potential and assign me as your leader?
I never cared about the results of those games in the first place.
そもそも　ゲームの勝敗など
私には問題ではない。
復讐　それが私の望み。
What I care about is revenge alone.
（ミゼルカ）
あっ！？
そのようなお話のために　私を！？
And that's why you made me...
ふ～っ…　紹介しよう。
Let me introduce you.
私が見つけた
次なるゲームのプレーヤーを。
I found the ideal player for our next game.
同行のお許しを
いただけませんか？
Would you allow me to accompany you?
かまわんよ。
せいぜい　勉強したまえ。
Sure, why not? Learn as much as you can.
そして　大門カイトと　その仲間に
死にも勝る屈辱と絶望を！
Give Daimon Kaito and his friends humiliation and despair
so deep they'll beg for death.
（キュービック）以上　中間報告　終わり。
Here's what I can tell you right now.
現状　ルークのくれた新型レプリカ・リングの
分析結果は　こんな感じだね。
This is all the data I could get from analyzing the replica ring Rook gave us.
（ギャモン）こんな感じってなぁ…
つまり　どんな感じなんだ？
All the data...
So what does it mean?
さっぱり　分かんねえぜ。
つまり　すごいの！
That's just a bunch of numbers to me.
It means it's amazing!
旧型より　はるかに高性能なの！
A lot better than the old one!
そして旧型よりも　はるかに過酷に
持ち主の脳をむしばむ。
It also puts a much larger strain on the user's brain.
こいつで　人間を
神々から解放するだと？
They want to free humankind from the gods with this?
笑わせやがるぜ。
オルペウス・オーダーの外道どもが。
Now there's a good joke...
You Orpheus Order jackasses...
ところで　カイトは　どうした？
By the way, where's Kaito?
We let Ana have him every now and then.
ああ！　たまには　アナにも
貸してあげないとね。
僕だけが独り占めするのも
大人気ないから。
It would be too childish to keep him all to myself.
あ～ん！？　何だ　そりゃ？
What... the hell?
あれ？　アナは？
Huh? Where's Ana?
誰？
さあ…。
Who's that?
Dunno.
（イブ）この絵のモデル…
君だったのね。
You modeled for this painting, right?
えっ！？　そうだけど…。
Yeah...
その絵見て　分かるんですか？
You can tell from the picture?
ナイーブで美しいタッチと　色使い…。
Naïve but beautiful stroke and colors.
モデルの　ほわわんな魂が
見事に描かれているわ。
The love-puff in the model's heart is obvious.
Love-puff? Is that Ana-lingo?
ほわわんって　アナ語！？
And the way the painter looked at the model with fluff-puff in his eyes...
そして　モデルを見つめる
ふわわんな視線。
作者は　君のことが大好きなのね。
He must love you a lot.
あのう…　誰っすか？
Uh... Who're you?
≫（アナ）イブ。
あっ…　あぁ？
Eve?
イブお姉ちゃん！
うふっ。
It's really you, Eve!
イブ！？…　あっ。
Eve?
回想
（アナ）アナに　かけられた
魔法を解いてくれた人。
She released me from the curse.
重たい殻の中から　アナを
回想
解き放ってくれた人。
She freed me from the heavy shell.
大好きなイブ。
回想
The Eve I love.
あの時　言ってた…。
わ～い！　イブだ　イブだ～！
He was talking about...
Whoa, it's Eve!
久しぶり　イブ～。
It's been so long, Eve!
本当に久しぶり。
元気そうね　アナ。
It certainly has... I'm glad to see you're doing well, Ana.
うん　元気！
Yeah, I am!
毎日楽しい？
うん　とっても　ふわわんなんだな。
Having fun every day?
Yeah, it's all fluff-puff!
そう。
Oh, really?
描いてるのね　絵…。
I see you've been painting.
すばらしいわ。
どんどん　うまくなってる。
They're wonderful. You've definitely improved.
はぁ…　イブには　かなわない。
I'm still not as good as you!
イブのほわほわ　ふわふわには
かなわないんだな。
This is nothing compared to the love-love fluff-fluff garden you painted.
それは…。
That's...
あの時　プラウダーホースで
俺に描いてくれた絵…。
what he painted for me back at the Prouder Horse.
イブが描いてくれた絵の模写。
It's a copy of what Eve painted for me.
笑うことを忘れていた
アナのために…。
When I forgot how to laugh...
笑うことを　忘れていた…。
Forgot how to laugh...
（アナ）イブの絵は　ほわほわ
ふわふわが　いっぱい。
Eve's painting was full of love and fluff.
だから…→
アナは　笑顔を思い出せた…。
It made me remember how to smile.
そんなことも…　あったわね。
Yeah, that... happened...
イブ…。
Eve!
触らないで…　汚らわしい。
Don't touch me.
How filthy.
（イブ）私は　あなたのために
生きてはいない！
I'm not living for you!
私は　私…。
あっ。
I am... me.
T-That's...
あっ　あれは…。
オルペウス・リング…。
An Orpheus ring!
（イブ）教えてあげる。
回想
Let me show you.
どんなに　心が凍えそうな
回想
時でも　きっと　心がポカポカになる→
No matter how down you're feeling, it'll warm your heart back up.
回想
そんな　おまじない。
ほわわん　ふわわん…。
It's that kind of a charm.
Love-puff, fluff-puff...
回想
ほわわん　ふわわん…。
Love-puff, fluff-puff...
回想
（アナ）お姉ちゃん…。
えっ！？　なあに　アナ？
Eve...
What is it, Ana?
ほわわんの絵　描いて。
回想
Paint me something fluffy.
できた～！　はい　アナ。
回想
Done!
Here, Ana!
ほわわん　ふわわん…。
回想
Love-puff! Fluff-puff!
アナ！　はっ。
回想
Ana!
ほわわん　ふわわん…。
Love-puff! Fluff-puff!
（イブ）大門カイト君　私のゲームに
挑戦してもらうわ。
Daimon Kaito! You are to challenge my game.
Why?
なんでだ！？　なんで　アナの
姉ちゃんが　オルペウス・オーダーなんかに！
Why would Ana's sister fall to the Orpheus Order?
How unpleasant.
不愉快ね　その言い方。
アナの姉だから　何？　私は　私よ。
So what if I'm Ana's sister? I am me.
アナを引き合いにして
私を語らないで。
Ana has nothing to do with our business.
（イブ）もっとも　アナが居るかぎり
私に自由はない…。
On the contrary, because Ana's here, I can't be free!
自由という名の
アナの独りよがりのせいで→
He has all the freedom, and because of his conceit...
私は…　人生をズタズタにされた。
My...
My life was ruined.
画家になるという夢を
捨てさせられたのよ！
I had to throw away my dream of becoming a painter!
なあに　その顔は？
少しは思い当たることがあって？
What's with that look?
Do you know what I'm talking about?
それとも　また笑顔を忘れたの？
Or did you forget how to smile again?
まあ　私には関係ないけど。
あんた！
Not that it has anything to do with me.
You!
If you lose the game, Ana will never paint again.
カイト君がゲームに負けたら　アナは
２度と絵が描けなくなるわ。
何だと！？　あっ！？
What?!
私が　腕を　へし折ってあげる。
I'll smash his arms to shreds.
どこまでも…　付きまとって…
必ず。
No matter how far I have to go.
ミゼルカ！
それでいいのか？　あんたは…。
Mizerka!
And you're okay with this?
もちろん。
そうか…。
Of course.
I see.
受けてやるぜ　このゲーム！
I accept your challenge!
許さねえ　オルペウス・オーダー！
You're gonna pay for this, Orpheus Order!
（ミゼルカ）まさか　こんな形で
あなたと再会するとはね。
To think we'd meet again like this.
しかも　アナへの復讐の機会が…。
And I can even get revenge on Ana.
Sorry for getting you mixed up in this, Mizerka.
巻き込んじゃってごめんね　ミゼルカ。
いいのよ。
私が言い出したんだから。
Don't worry about it. I'm here of my own will.
手伝いたいの。
ありがとう…。
I want to help.
Thanks.
私は　私から絵を奪ったアナを
許さない。
I'll make Ana pay for robbing me of painting.
大門カイトともども　私の中から
消し去る…。
I'll make him vanish along with Daimon Kaito!
頑張ってね　イブ。
見届けるわ…　親友として…。
Good luck, Eve.
I'll be watching...
As your best friend...
オルペウス・オーダーの一員として
同じ　ファイ・ブレインの子供として…。
As a member of the Orpheus Order...
As a fellow child of the Phi Brain...
準備はいい？
ああ…。
Are you ready?
Yeah.
あっ　これは！
What?
（イブ）君に挑戦してもらうパズルよ。
ルールは簡単。
It's the puzzle you must challenge.
The rules are simple.
１１時４５分にスタートし　１５分で　全ての
欠片を　隙間なく　枠に収めて→
You start at 11:45 and in fifteen minutes you must
complete the picture from the fragments so that it fits within frame.
１枚の絵を完成させれば
君の勝ち。
Then you win.
敷き詰めパズルか。
A simple tiling puzzle.
久しぶりに絵を描いたわ。
アナ　あなたのためにね。
I painted a picture after such a long time.
I painted it for you, Ana.
（時を刻む音）
パズルタイムの始まりだ。
It's puzzle time!
あっ！　これは！？
What?!
全部　真っ黒じゃない！
They're all pitch black!
あんなの　どうやって
組み合わせろっていうのよ！
How do you expect anyone to solve that?!
一見　真っ黒だが…
複数の色を組み合わせている。
It looks black at first glance,
but it's actually a mix of colors.
微妙な絵の具の配置と　筆の流れ。
それを目安にするしか…。
A grotesque use of colors and strokes.
I can use that as a clue.
ジグソーパズルなら　四隅の欠片を
最初に見つけるのが　セオリーだが→
In a jigsaw puzzle, you usually find the four corners first,
こいつには　通用しねえ…。
but that doesn't apply here.
（時を刻む音）
うっ。　やるっきゃねえ！
Here I go!
この欠片に合うのは！？
Which one fits here?
違う。　この欠片か！
No. What about this?
違う！
カイト…。
No!
Kaito...
（イブ）あなたのために描いたのよ。
少しは喜んでよ。
I painted it for you.
At least pretend to be happy.
それとも　本当に忘れちゃったの？
笑顔…。
Or have you really forgotten how to smile?
イブさん。
いい気なものね。
Eve...
How dare you.
私の苦しみも知らず
自由気ままに…。
You don't even know my suffering, you just go on freely...
吐き気がするわ！
You make me sick.
あぁ…。
（アナ）あの絵は…。
That painting...
どうしたの？　アナ。
あの絵って…。
What's wrong, Ana?
What painting?
あっ　そっか！
Ah, I see!
アナは　バラバラの欠片からでも
パズルの絵柄を認識できる…。
You can see the whole picture just by looking at the fragments.
あのパズルが完成したときの絵も
分かるのね。
Do you know what that painting is supposed to look like?
（イブ）相変わらず
薄気味悪いほどの才能ね。
Eerie genius as always.
でも　その才能が
私から絵を奪った。
But your genius robbed me of painting!
よし！　次は…。
Okay! Next...
こいつには
分かりやすい特徴がある。
That one has quite a unique look.
対応するのは　どれだ？　どれだ！
Which one matches it?
Which one?!
アナに絵を教えたのは…　私。
I taught you how to paint.
私の絵で　笑顔を取り戻したアナは
絵を描く喜びに目覚めた。
When I taught Ana how to smile again,
he found the joy in painting.
もちろん　最初は
幼稚な　いたずら描き。
Of course, it was all just childish doodling at first.
でも…　ほどなく　一気に
才能を開花させ→
However, his genius quickly developed, and I was left in his dust.
私を抜き去っていった…。
アナの絵には　私にはない
輝きがあった。
Ana's pictures shone like mine never could.
人の心をとらえて離さない輝き→
They caught people's hearts and never let go.
自由な…
自由奔放な魂の輝きが…。
So free... The eternal sunshine of a free soul.
自由な魂…　けれど　それは
求めても決して手に入らないもの。
A free soul...
But that's not something you can get just by wanting it.
だから　私は絵筆を捨てた。
So I had to throw the brush away.
分かる？　弟に踏み台にされた
私の屈辱が…　怒りが…。
Can you understand?
The humiliation and anger I felt when my own brother used me as a stepping stone!
憎い！　アナの自由な魂が！
I hate you! Your free soul!
アナの自由が
憎くてたまらないのよ！
I hate your freedom more than anything!
あぁ。
何よ　それ…　どうして比べるの？
What's wrong with you? Why are you comparing yourself to him?
なんですって？
アナは　アナ…。
イブさんは　イブさんじゃない…。
What?!
Ana is Ana! You are you!
Why do you make him responsible for you binding yourself?!
どうして　自分で　自分を縛って
その責任をアナに押し付けるの！
Ana made me!
そうさせたのよ　アナが！
何よ　その目！
What's with that look?
Are you going to lock yourself in your shell again
また　昔みたいに殻に閉じこもって
だんまりを決め込む気？
and just stay silent like you used to?
I won't let you!
そんなの許さないわ！
謝りなさい！
Apologize!
地べたに頭をこすりつけ　泣いて
私に許しを請いなさいよ！
Throw yourself on the floor and tearfully beg for my forgiveness!
うわっ！　こ　これは！
This...
（時を刻む音）
さあ　早く！
Do it now!
この絵は　アナ…　アナが…！
This painting... Ana...
ダメ！　謝ったりしちゃ　ダメ！
アナは悪くない！
No! You mustn't apologize!
You did nothing wrong! Don't give in to her mad hatred!
そんな　ゆがんだ憎しみに
謝る必要なんかない！
ほわわん…。
えっ！？
Love-puff...
Huh?
ほわわん…　ふわわん…。
Love-puff... Fluff-puff...
何よ！？　何のつもり？
What? What is that even?
おまじない。　イブが教えてくれた
凍えた心が　ポカポカになる…。
The charm you taught me.
It will warm even the iciest of hearts.
ふざけないで！　そんな
口からでまかせ　引っ張り出して→
Don't screw with me!
Why are you bringing up that random nonsense now?!
どこまで　おめでたいのよ！
What do you even think?!
そんなことで　私の心が…　心が…。
My heart would never... never...
うわっ　解きたくねえ。
I don't want to solve this.
もう　これ以上は…
このパズルだけは…。
No further... Anything but this...
けど　解かなきゃ　アナが…。
But I must solve it for Ana...
≪（アナ）解いていい！
あっ！
You can solve it!
カイト！　解いて！　カイト～！
Kaito, solve it! Kaito!
Kaito!
カイト～！
これで　最後だ～！
It's over!
It's... disgusting.
何？　このおぞましい絵…。
これが　イブの…　アナへの思い。
Those are Eve's feelings toward me.
空っぽだったぜ。
（２人）あっ。
It's empty.
Kaito!
カイト。
あんたのパズルには何もねえ。
Your puzzle had nothing.
空っぽだった。　絵も　パズルも同じ。
It's empty. The painting and the puzzle too.
今の　あんたが描く絵は
空っぽなんだろうな。
You only paint empty pictures now, right?
でも　俺には　それが
本物のあんただと思えない。
But I don't think that's really you.
アナの笑顔を取り戻した
あんただとは…。
You taught Ana to smile again.
イブの敵！
えっ！？
This is for Eve!
やめて～！
はっ！
Stop!
やめて…　もういいの…　もう…。
Stop... please just let it end...
イブ…。
Eve...
あぁ。
ごめんなさい。　イブお姉ちゃん。
I'm so sorry, Eve...
ごめんなさい…　ごめんなさい…。
（泣き声）
I'm so sorry... So sorry!
心の声
（ミゼルカ）イブのリングは　レプリカ。
イブは　実験体…。
Eve's ring was a replica.
It was just an experiment.
I believed... that she would be a child of the Phi Brain just like me.
信じていたのに　彼女も
心の声
私と同じ　ファイ・ブレインの子供だと…。
（ギャモン）とんだ災難だったな　カイト…。
That was one hell of a mess, Kaito.
ああ…。
（キュービック）でも　もう大丈夫。
Yeah.
But it's all right now!
リングから解放されて　理性と思考の
ひずみは　完全に払拭されたから。
Her warped logic and reasoning is gone now that she's been released from the ring.
彼女は　ＰＯＧが責任を持って
オルペウス・オーダーから守るわ。
The POG will take responsibility to protect her from the Orpheus Order.
頼むぜ　メイズ！
Thanks, Maze!
アナには　かなわないけれど…
私　もう一度　絵を描いてみる。
I'm no match for you, but I'll try painting again.
私は　アナの絵が好きよ。
もっと見てみたい。
I like your paintings.
I'd love to see more of them.
だから　もっともっと描いてね。
ふっ。
So paint more, okay?
じゃあね…。
See ya.
うそ…。
えっ！？
You lie...
アナには　分かる。
イブは　もう…　絵を描かない…。
I know.
Eve will never paint again.
もう　イブの絵が…　見られない。
I'll never see her paintings again!
アナ…。
Ana...
Kaito!
カイト～！
I loved... I loved her paintings!
アナは　アナは大好きだったのに！
（泣き声）
今度は　お前の番だ。
It's your turn now.
お前の絵で　姉ちゃんに
本当の笑顔を取り戻してやれ。
Use your paintings to teach your sister how to smile with her heart again.
Yeah.
eiyuu kidori itsu datte shinjita muteki no kankaku
I think I'm a hero and believe that I'm invincible.
tatakatte iru no wa chikyuu no tame nanka janai
I'm not fighting for the world.
motto mai peesu de
It's for a more personal,
sou motto shoujikina negai no tame
a more honest wish.
nando to naku kizutsuite mo
No matter how many times I'm hurt